<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="../Schema/poem_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<content>
    <about>
        <poemTitle xml:id="host">Host</poemTitle>
        <accArt/>
        <bgInfo>
            <p>Host was written for a Creative Writing course in May of 2019, when I was in my
                second year of college</p>
            <p>This poem is, on the surface, about someone discovering something living within them.
                This parasite takes over their body over the course of the work, and by the end, the
                parasite and host are one.</p>
            <p>This is mean to communicate the feeling of mental illness and how it encroaches into
                your personality and identity. I struggle a lot with my mental health, and I have
                felt at times that the darker parts of myself, the illness, consumes me whole.</p>
        </bgInfo>
        <themes>
            <themePoint>Mental Health</themePoint>
            <themePoint>Paranoia</themePoint>
            <themePoint>Parasite/Host</themePoint>
        </themes>
        <lineInfo>
            <lineInfoPoint passageRef="l1">This person's mental illness, that darkness inside of
                them, is becoming uncontrollable. It <q>wants out</q>, to present itself
                freely.</lineInfoPoint>
            <lineInfoPoint passageRef="l4"><q>It slowly kills,</q> mental illness is draining --
                it's a killer of the mind and emotions. It sucks the life out of you, as much as it
                can, like a parasite sucking the blood of its host.</lineInfoPoint>
            <lineInfoPoint passageRef="l6 l7">Their own sense of self is fading into their mental
                illness.</lineInfoPoint>
            <lineInfoPoint passageRef="l18">It has take over; this person's issue, whatever it may
                be (depression, anxiety, schizophrenia, etc). has consumed them.</lineInfoPoint>
        </lineInfo>
        <metaTags>
            <tagPoint tag="parasite"/>
            <tagPoint tag="parasites"/>
            <tagPoint tag="paranoia"/>
            <tagPoint tag="imposter-syndrome"/>
            <tagPoint tag="fear"/>
            <tagPoint tag="anxiety"/>
            <tagPoint tag="isolation"/>
            <tagPoint tag="mental-health"/>
            <tagPoint tag="mental-illness"/>
        </metaTags>

        <credit>
            <creditPoint> </creditPoint>
        </credit>
    </about>

    <poem>
        <stanza stanzaNum="s1">
            <line lineNum="l1">The thing that lives inside of me wants out.</line>
        </stanza>

        <stanza stanzaNum="s2">
            <line lineNum="l2">It has tendrils threaded like muscle that have wrapped around the
                beating of my heart, </line>
            <line lineNum="l3">taking hostage the pumping of my blood in demand of something unknown
                to me.</line>
        </stanza>

        <stanza stanzaNum="s3">
            <line lineNum="l4">But, it slowly kills, and through the hollow pupil of my eye,</line>
            <line lineNum="l5">I can see the writhing of some fleshy mass suckling at the wrinkles
                of my brain.</line>
            <line lineNum="l6">It’s as though I lose myself when it pulses;</line>
            <line lineNum="l7">my consciousness fades in a sick rhythm as the pressure pulls tighter
                like</line>
            <line lineNum="l8">a bow string ready to snap.</line>
        </stanza>

        <stanza stanzaNum="s4">
            <line lineNum="l9">I’m getting too big for my body,</line>
            <line lineNum="l10">overfilled with meat and bone and ready to burst out at the
                seams.</line>
            <line lineNum="l11">It pushes at my nerves, presses against the skin,</line>
            <line lineNum="l12">and now threads poke out my nostrils,</line>
            <line lineNum="l13">slither out the canals of my ears,</line>
            <line lineNum="l14">birthing from my throat to shroud around my tongue,</line>
            <line lineNum="l15">weaving through the gaps of my teeth,</line>
        </stanza>

        <stanza stanzaNum="s5">
            <line lineNum="l16">and I can feel it.</line>
            <line lineNum="l17">I can feel now.</line>
        </stanza>

        <stanza stanzaNum="s6">
            <line lineNum="l18">I am you.</line>
        </stanza>

    </poem>
</content>
